Register to the United States Office of War Information Psychological Warfare Division propaganda
Hoover Institution Archives
United States Office of War Information Psychological Warfare Division propaganda
1942-1945
XX372
United States. Office of War Information. Psychological Warfare Division.
2 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (1.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives
Propaganda leaflets distributed in Europe and in the China-Burma-India Theater of operations during World War II. Includes translations of most Asian language material.
Access
The collection is open for research.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Scope and Contents Note
The collection contains propaganda leaflets distributed in Europe and in the China-Burma-India Theater of operations during World War II. Produced by the U.S. Office of War Information, leaflets were dropped from planes inside enemy territory and in countries invaded by the enemy. Propaganda leaflets, pictorial newspapers, and "gift drops" were widely used to weaken enemy morale, encourage the resistance, and befriend the people from the occupied countries. Collection includes translations of most Asian language material.
Propaganda, American.; World War, 1939-1945--Propaganda.
- European Theater World War II leaflets, 1942-1945 (Box 1)
  - German
    - Leaflets (Box-folder 1: 1-8)
    - Frankfurter Zeitung issues (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - French (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Italian (Box-folder 1: 11)
- Pacific Theatre World War II leaflets, 1942-1945 (Box 1-2)
  - All languages (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - American propaganda leaflets (TF series) (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - Vietnamese/French, 1944-1945
    - Action leaflets, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 1: 14)
    - Pictorial News leaflets, 1944 (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - Burmese, 1944-1945
    - Action leaflets, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 1: 16)
    - Morale leaflets, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 1: 17)
    - Pictorial leaflets, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 1: 18)
  - Chinese, 1944-1945
    - Action leaflets, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 1: 19-21)
    - Morale leaflets, 1945 (Box-folder 2: 1)
    - News leaflets, 1944 (Box-folder 2: 2-5)
      - Information sheets, 1944 (Box-folder 2: 2)
      - Liberty Pictorial, 1945 February-August (Box-folder 2: 3)
      - News Highlights, 1945 February-September (Box-folder 2: 4)
      - News Pictorial, 1944 December-1945 August (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Chinese and Japanese, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - Formosa (Taiwan), 1944-1945 (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - Japanese, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 2: 8-13)
    - Action leaflet, undated (Box-folder 2: 8)
    - Morale, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 2: 9-11)
    - News, 1945 (Box-folder 2: 12)
    - Various, 1945 (Box-folder 2: 13)
  - Korean, 1944 October-1945 January (Box-folder 2: 14)
  - Thai, 1945 (Box-folder 2: 15)
- Miscellany: typed lecture on psychological warfare, sewing kit, and unidentified object, undated (Box-folder 2: 16)
- Leaflet book, oversize leaflets, 1944-1945 (Box 3)